Jayanth Arawa (Jay)

Senior Frontend JavaScript Developer with a passion for learning and creating engaging and intuitive user interface with over 10 years of experience building fast, modern websites and web applications. Committed to a growth mindset and staying up-to-date with industry trends.

https://lifeofjayantharawa.web.app/ jayantharawa@gmail.com

355 Grape Lane, Boulder, CO (410) 245-9383

EXPERIENCE

Charter Communications, Greenwood Village CO — *Lead UI developer*

December 2022 - PRESENT

Created new Angular component library with documentation promoting code reuse and best practices

Built the PRISM Next Generation portal using Angular 14 from scratch and mentored developers, expanding their knowledge of component architecture, JavaScript, Angular, and CSS patterns

The Boeing Company, Englewood CO — Lead UI Fullstack developer/Salesforce Admin

May 2020 - November 2022

Winner of first Boeing Hackathon for building an AI bot using Salesforce Einstein bot and Experience Cloud.

Led team of 5 building custom websites and web applications.

Drive a remote dev team.

Built and maintained the Jeppesen support portal using Angular 11, Redux(NgRX), LWC, APEX, Experience Cloud, Salesforce Einstein bot.

Helped design look and feel along with UX/UI team

Comcast, Denver CO — Fullstack Lead Developer

March 2019 - April 2020

Built Confidential tool using Angular, RXJS, and NGRX platform.

Developed components as an independent module for reusability across the application (microservices).

Primary focus on React, ReactNative, Angular, NodeJS.

Drive software development activities to meet schedules and timelines Thrives to ensure code quality is high with supporting unit tests and automation, and timely delivery.

Carefirst + **CSOSA**, Washington DC — *UI Fullstack Developer*

March 2018 - September 2019

Developed Angular and NodeJS web application for real-time communication among users.

LANGUAGES

HTML, CSS, Sass, Less, JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Java, .NET, Python, Apex.

FRAMEWORKS

Angular (Versions 2 - 14), AngularJS, React, LWC, NodeJS, Jest, Jasmine, Redux, NgRX.

SKILLS

Salesforce, Azure, Git, SVN, Bootstrap, Material Design, CSS Media Queries, 508 compliance, Flexbox, ES5, ES6, ES7, RESTful APIs, JSON, AJAX.

Algorithms, Mobile Web Design, Responsive Design, Cross-browser compatibility and performance optimization, Unit Tests (Jasmine & Karma), MySQL, MongoDB, Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop

Scrum, Agile methodology, Jira



Used Angular to create reusable components, consumed REST APIs to retrieve data from the database, and Angular Pipes to filter the data to display it in the materialized view.

Comcast, Philadelphia — *UI Developer*

May 2017 - March 2018



Led accessibility improvements to achieve 100% WCAG 2.0 AA compliance.

Planned, coded, and delivered greenfield project from the ground up.

International Monetary Fund, Washington DC — *UI-UX Developer*

March 2016 - April 2017

Migrated production legacy application from Angular JS (angular 1.5.5) to Angular 2+ framework.

Crafted responsive, scalable user interfaces with AngularJS/2 in coordination with the security team to eliminate vulnerabilities.

Mphasis, Chennai, India— Web/UI Developer

July 2012 (12-13 internship) - June 2014

Designed and developed prototypes such as wireframes, flowcharts, screen mock-ups, and interface design

Created robust RESTful web services in Java with Spring Boot framework through the use of JPA and Hibernate and designed end-points to integrate with front-end.



EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science Engineering – Vishveswaraya Technological University, India (2013)

Master's degree in Computer science in the track of Computer Science – **Towson university Baltimore Maryland(2015)**

CERTIFICATIONS

Salesforce Admin Certified

Salesforce Experience Could Certified

ACHIEVEMENTS

Played professional cricket (Ranji Trophy) for the state of Karnataka in India